Olamide Faniyan

Email: faniyanolamide@gmail.com | Nigeria

Front-End Developer | Portfolio | GitHub | LinkedIn

Profile ←	
Profile 4	h
1 101116	

I am a keen learner who grasp any opportunity to further my personal and professional development. I am a Front-End Software Developer with over 2 years of front-end experience, and majority of my day-to-day activity is learning, general life development or a new language or framework. I have taken numerous steps to pursue my long-term career goal of becoming a Software Developer. I won many scholarships to further my software development, among them is the just concluded Udacity/Access bank Cohort. I gained valuable experience with a variety of technologies and the best practices within front-end development.

Apart from my technical skills, I developed exceptional communication and teamwork organizational skills at my previous role where I was made to have a compulsory relationship with not only technical coworkers but also Designers, Project Managers, and Management. I am actively interested in a role where I can showcase my technical skills as well as my soft skills in the IT sector. I am a firm believer of mobile-first approach

Core Knowledge & Skills ←

Understanding of Multiples Technologies ~ HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React, JQuery, Tailwind CSS, Material UI, Figma, Git/GitHub, Contentful CMS

Knowledge of the following Technologies ~ TypeScript, Apollo-Client (GraphQL) Python

General Skills ~ MS Office: Word; Excel; PowerPoint, Strong and Fluent communication skills (English), Team Player, Ready to learn, Organizational skills

Professional Experience

Side Hustle.

October 2021 - January 2022

Coding Traineeship

Development and implementation of an anti-bullying website of which I was in charge of the front-end development using React.js, tailwind CSS and material UI.

Actively participated in team events and was able to make use of the teams communication channel like Slack, Google meet thereby developing my soft skills.

Collaborated with product team members to implement features on a website / web-app which include mobile responsibility

Worked with the structure of software development already in use with the following technologies:

- HTML5 and CSS3, Tailwind CSS, Material UI
- Javascript, Majorly React
- Git / GitHub
- Contentful CMS
- Apollo-client, Apollo Server (GraphQL)

Udacity / Access Bank Tech Sponsorship.

September 2021 - January 2022

Programming Scholarship

A Two-Phased program that started with about 2,000 people and only 500 will be selected to the next round of which I was among those who succeeded.

It was a fast-paced event which easily honed my problem-solving skill and ability to work under pressure.

Development of different software like a word-based game, a pixel picker and many others using the technologies below

- Python
- Javascript
- CSS3
- HTML5
- Git / GitHub

Education & Certifications -

September 2021 - January 2022

Introduction to programming nanodegree program using HTML, CSS, Javascript and Python.

BABCOCK UNIVERSITY.

September 2017 – September 2020

B.Sc. Computer Science (Computer Information Systems). I graduated university with a bachelor's degree in Computer science upper credit (2.1). I was part of the Google Developers group (GDG) in my School.

Interests ←

- Sports ~ Football (Soccer), Formula 1 (F1), Tennis, Snooker
- Video games ~ Fifa, GTA, Red Dead Redemption
- Evening walks

References ←

References available upon request